Do you remember
the last thing that you said to me?
"She's alive."
Have you finished Cold Harbor?
What is this place?
It's a cabin for giving birth.
Why am I here? Why are you here?
Cold Harbor.
Have you finished it?
No.
Then she's still alive.
We can save her.
Who?
Ms. Casey.
Gemma.
There's a hallway down there.
It's different than the others.
It's long and black and hidden.
From Irving's drawings.
What?
With an elevator going down.
We know where it is.
What a funny speech you gave at the party.
I was cross with you after.
I threw a tin of candies.
God, you're fucking weird.
I do not love my daughter.
I used to see Kier in her,
but he left her as she grew.
You sound like a great dad.
I sired others in the shadows.
But he wasn't in them either.
Until I saw him again.
In you.
You and your family created hell,
and you're going to burn in it.
There he is.
Tomorrow is a special day.
Hey!
Why did you come here?
What do you want from me?
So, wait, when I finish Cold Harbor,
they do a test, and then they kill her?
Once that file is done, you'll need
to quickly get to the black hallway,
then down to the testing floor.
They'll not let you leave MDR
till that file is complete.
Okay, but how do I find her
once I'm down there?
No, you won't.
- I won't?
- No.
Your chip is only attuned to your floor.
Once you get down to testing,
you'll be your outie again.
And then he'll find Gemma
and take her up to the severed floor.
Where you will guide her
to the exit stairwell.
Right. Okay.
Mark...
I know this is a fucking lot, man.
But if we can prove that she is alive,
if we can prove
that they fucking kidnapped her,
it will end them.
Well, what happens to us?
What do you mean?
Well, if Lumon ends, then what happens
to every innie on the severed floor?
Yeah.
- You want me to give my life?
- No.
The lives of everyone down there?
No, it's not that simple.
Just to save one person
you happen to care about?
It doesn't have to end your life.
Really?
Right.
There's somebody else
who wants to talk to you, actually.
Okay, just hit the play.
Watch it.
Record your response, then step outside.
We'll just be downstairs, okay?
Okay.
Hey, I'm...
Well, I guess you know who I am.
I think you've spoken
with Devon and Mrs. Sel...
Ms. Cobel.
So y...
you know what it is that we're asking.
But the first thing I need to say to you
is that I am so sorry.
You know, I created you
as a prisoner and as an escape.
Lumon told me you'd be happy,
that innies are content,
and because I took their word for it,
you've been living a nightmare
for two years.
It's horrific what they've done to you.
And part of the reason I'm here
is to make it right.
And I hope now with all we have in common,
that you'll give me that chance.
Hi.
Wow, this is...
I never expected to actually speak to you.
Holy shit.
Let alone get an apology, so...
Thank you.
You know, "nightmare"
is the wrong word, actually.
'Cause we find ways to make it work, to...
to feel whole,
which is why what you're asking scares me.
You know, because whatever this life is...
it's all we have,
and we don't want it to end.
Can you understand that?
Of course I can.
It's such a good point.
I'd say the same thing
in your position, however,
Lumon doesn't have to be your whole life.
Now, you may have been
seeing flashes lately.
Images from my world out here.
I've been seeing yours too.
It's a process called "reintegration."
It's a way to recouple memories
so we can be one person.
I started this because I see now
how unfair this all is to you,
and once my wife is free,
I swear I will finish the process.
'Cause this life, our life...
belongs to both of us.
And I wanna share it with you.
Okay. But what would that mean exactly?
That you get the right side,
and I get the left? Or...
Is it like a top-bottom situation? I'm--
- No.
- I'm honestly trying to understand.
No, it wouldn't be like
a top-bottom situation.
It's, like, both of us.
Like, one person combined.
Like, my memories and yours,
and my trauma and yours,
but, like, you know, the good stuff too.
Okay, but...
I mean, you've been alive for, what,
20 times longer,
so whoever this new hybrid person is,
it seems like
he'd be way more you than me.
I just don't think that's how it works.
Okay. How does it work?
Look...
I mourned Gemma for two years.
I lost my job, my teaching job...
because I fucking started
showing up drunk.
You know, I hid all of her stuff
in my basement...
'cause it was easier pretending
that she never existed.
And I thought I was protecting you
from that pain.
Hey, Ms. Cobel told me
you like someone down there?
Helena Eagan, right?
I think her innie name's "Heleny"?
Honestly,
I love that you had that experience.
So, now you could imagine,
like, what you and Heleny have
but multiply, like, thousands of days
of, like, joy, and arguments, and passion,
then you can see why
I have to get my wife back.
I have to have her back.
It's Helly, actually. Helly.
It's the person I'm in love with,
which you'd know if you'd ever
taken an interest in my life.
Before tonight, when you need something.
She's the person I'll lose
if I do what you say
'cause you know as well as I do
that her outie won't, like, reintegrate,
assuming that's even real.
Assuming every word
outta your mouth isn't a lie.
Wha...
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
Dude, I'm just trying
to save my wife, okay?
I mean, I can't abandon her,
and if you help me,
I won't abandon you. I promise.
You know what I think? I think
the second you get your wife back,
you forget I ever existed.
I think that I disappear
along with every innie down there.
What do you want from me?
We are in this together.
Can't you just trust me?
No.
Devon!
He's a fucking child. He won't listen.
Let me speak to him.
I mentioned reintegration,
he basically called bullshit.
Well, he's not wrong, right?
Let me speak to him.
Alone.
Okay. Yeah.
Okay.
The numbers are your wife.
The MDR numbers.
From your console.
They're a doorway into the mind
of your outie's wife, Gemma Scout.
I don't understand.
What do you see every day
when you look at them?
What... we feel things.
What do you feel?
Different things. Sometimes sadness...
Woe.
Frolic.
Malice.
Dread.
So you're saying the...
the clusters are...
Her tempers.
The building blocks of her mind.
What am I building?
Every file you've completed...
is a new consciousness for her.
A new innie.
I've completed 24 files.
Cold Harbor is the last.
Tomorrow will be your final day at Lumon.
You will have served your purpose,
and so will she.
Wait, why are you telling me this?
What are you doing here, really?
Mark. Mark.
There'll be no honeymoon ending
for you and Helly R.
She's an Eagan.
You're nothing to them.
- No.
- Nothing to her.
No, I don't believe you.
They're using you.
No! I don't believe you!
Then they'll discard you like a skin husk.
- I think you're using me!
- Mark!
- Reintegration is your only chance!
- Wait.
- Do you love your brother?
- Mark!
Yes.
Well, then you tell him
that the next thing I see
had better be the severed floor,
or I swear he will never
see his wife again.
I care for you.
Stop!
Mark.
I have to tell you something.
Me too.
Fuck me.
"Mark, The Founder wished to witness
the historic completion of your 25th file.
Helly R. shall also bear witness
from her chair.
Goodly splendors await upon your victory.
Love, Mr. Milchick."
Jame Eagan was here.
He came to see me.
He said some cryptic shit
about the fire of Kier being in me,
and that today is a special day.
I know why.
I know why they're doing this.
Hello, Dylan.
He said no?
Follow me.
So, what happens
when they extract the chip?
But how can we trust anything Cobel says?
All she's ever done is lie.
I know, but she seemed different.
I mean, she's the same, but,
like, different same.
I don't know.
I mean, I could just not do it.
I could just not finish the file,
not get her out.
But if she's telling the truth,
we're screwed either way.
What's happening?
Just get dressed.
Everything is gonna be fine.
But if you get her out, maybe that will
take down Lumon, like his sister said.
And maybe you can do this combining thing.
Well, yeah, but he could be a total liar.
What if he's not?
At least you'll have a chance at living.
Yeah, but I wanna live with you.
But I'm her, Mark.
I'm her.
Okay.
Your outie has responded
to your resignation request.
As it may yield an embarrassing
emotional response in you,
and as I'm duly swamped,
I shall leave you to read it in solitude.
"Dear innie,
I've read your request and organized
my response into three points.
Point one: fuck you."
Gretchen is my wife and my beloved,
and your actions with her
were deeply fucking indecorous.
Point two:
I get it.
She's perfect, and given our shared
physiology, it tracks that you'd agree.
Here's the thing.
I've never been an impressive person,
so when Gretch told me that
you're, like, this self-assured badass,
I don't know.
It stung.
So I guess, point three is:
I hope someday she sees in me
what she sees in you.
In the meantime,
if I'm being really honest,
I guess I like knowing you're there.
So if you wanna leave, you can.
But I think you should stay.
Sincerest regards, Your outie.
Been trying to think
of other place names besides Delaware.
I've got Europe, Zimbabwe...
and the Equator.
The Equator?
Is that a building?
Or a continent.
Maybe it's just a building
that's, like, so big...
That it became a continent.
Yeah.
I just wish we had more time.
Least it's a happy one.
Call Mr. Eagan.
Mark S.,
in completing your 25th Macrodata file,
you have drawn my grand agendum
nearer to fulfillment,
thus making you
one of the most
important people in history.
Revel now in the fruit of your labors,
and hail your earthbound steward,
your very own...
floor manager!
Thank you, Kier.
And may I say,
you're looking very handsome, sir.
Thank you.
I'd say the same of you,
if not for my favorite core principle.
Probity?
No.
Vision.
Well, it's truly special
to host a man so illustrious,
so sapient, so magnanimous--
My, you're verbose.
Good thing you didn't write
the first appendix.
It would've burst.
It's an honor to receive your barbs,
Mr. Eagan.
The legacy you've left behind
is truly and irrefutably larger than life.
You mean my company?
No.
I mean this wax statue that's five inches
taller than you actually were.
Thank you for that feedback...
Seth.
Thank you, Kier.
And now, lady and gentleman of MDR,
may I introduce
Choreography and Merriment!
Let's go.
Mark!
Welcome, Mr. Eagan.
The efficacy test will begin shortly.
Thank you, C&M.
Let's keep the Mark S. love going...
I have to leave.
...with the Ballad of Ambrose
and Gunnel.
You ready?
Yeah.
See you at the Equator.
Hey. Can I get a little help?
Hey!
Can I get a little help here?
Helly.
Where's Mark?
I don't know!
- Hey.
- Yeah.
Enter the room.
Who are you?
I don't know.
Mammalians Nurturable brings an offering.
Has it verve?
It does.
Wiles?
The most of its flock.
This beast will be entombed
with a cherished woman,
whose spirit it must guide to Kier's door.
Is it up to the task?
It is.
Then give me its life.
Take it apart.
Helly!
Excuse me.
We commit this animal to Kier,
and his eternal war against pain.
How many?
How many what?
How many more must I give?
As many as the Founder calls.
Mark S.
Wrong door.
I'm leaving, okay?
Oh, fuck.
No more killing.
Wait, wait, wait!
Wait! Wait.
Please. Please. Please.
The barrier is holding.
She feels nothing.
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
Emile thanks you.
Emile is the name of the goat.
Okay.
Now, in a second
I'm gonna change to my outie,
and then you are gonna take him to--
What are you doing?
Those instruments are property
of Choreography and Merriment.
Choreography and Merriment,
return to your department now!
Fall back to C&M.
Our performance has been compromised.
No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait.
Wait.
This desk used to have four seats.
Our friend Irving is gone,
and they want our whole department gone.
If he gets out, we're dead.
They're gonna turn us off
like fucking machines.
You've seen them do it.
I know you've lost friends too.
And you could be next.
You could be next.
They give us half a life
and think we won't fight for it.
Right, Milchick?
Please, help us.
Please.
Help us.
- How did you get in here?
- Jesus.
Open the door.
- Step off, fucko.
- Do it.
- No! No! No! No! No!
- Now. Do it! Go! Go!
No! No, fuck you! Fuck you!
No! Dr. Mauer! Fuck you!
Jesus. Fuck.
Gemma?
It's okay. It's me.
I'm your husband.
Okay.
Your name is Gemma Scout.
We'd been married for four years.
No.
We were...
We had a life together...
Don't speak to that man.
He's here to hurt you.
And if you come with me right now,
we can get it back.
No.
Stop.
This is not a part of the test.
- Please.
- Don't let him touch you.
We have to go.
Stop!
Oh, fuck.
Mr. Drummond. Mr. Drummond. Damn!
It's okay.
Fuck!
It's the fucking spouse!
Call Drummond!
Okay. You can come. It's okay.
Come on.
Come on out.
It's okay.
Mark.
Come on.
Gemma!
Gemma. Stop!
No, no, no.
No.
You'll kill them all!
Mark S.?
Ms. Casey.
What's taking place?
Come on.
Okay. Come on.
Okay.
- You have to go right now. Go.
- Where?
Come on! You gotta go right now!
Go.
Fuck you, Mr. Milchick.
Mark. Mark, come on.
Come on, Mark.
Come on. We have to go.
Mark! Mark, open the door. Come on.
What are you doing?
Open the door.
Mark, we gotta go home.
Mark.
Mark, come on. Mark, open the door.
Mark, you have to come.
Open the door. Come on.
Mark.
Mark!
What? Mark!
Mark! Mark!
Goddamn it, Mark,
we have to get out of here.
Mark! Mark! We have to get out of here!
Mark! Mark, we gotta go.
Mark.
Mark! Mark!
Mark! Mark, no. No. Mark.
Mark.
Mark! Open the door! Mark!
No! Mark!
Mark! Come back!
Mark!